<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Playbook><Section title="Präambel"><Clause><Text>Dieser Vertrag regelt die Lieferung von Standardkomponenten (Spezifikation gemäß Anhang A) durch den Lieferanten an den Käufer. Qualität und Zuverlässigkeit sind wesentliche Kriterien. Dieser Vertrag regelt die Lieferung von Standardkomponenten (Spezifikation gemäß Anhang A) durch den Lieferanten an den Käufer. Qualität und Zuverlässigkeit sind wesentliche Kriterien.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>The contract should specify that the supplier guarantees the highest quality and reliability of the standard components, with a defect rate not exceeding 0.1%.</Description><Justification>This ensures that the customer receives top-quality components, minimizing potential issues and costs associated with defects.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Given the critical nature of these components in our operations, we need the assurance of the highest quality and reliability. A defect rate of 0.1% or less is industry standard for high-quality components.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>The contract should state that the supplier will provide standard components that meet or exceed industry-standard quality and reliability benchmarks.</Description><Justification>This ensures that the components meet widely accepted standards, balancing cost and quality.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Meeting industry-standard benchmarks is a reasonable expectation that balances our need for quality with your production capabilities.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>The contract should specify that the supplier will provide standard components that meet the agreed-upon quality and reliability specifications outlined in Anhang A.</Description><Justification>This ensures that the components meet the agreed-upon standards, though it may not exceed industry benchmarks.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Adhering to the specifications in Anhang A is crucial for our operations. While it may not exceed industry standards, it meets our immediate needs.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>The contract should state that the supplier will provide standard components with no guarantee of quality or reliability.</Description><Justification>This leaves the customer with no assurance of the component quality, posing significant risks to operations and potential additional costs.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Accepting components without any quality or reliability guarantee is not feasible for our operations. We need at least a basic assurance of quality to protect our interests.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 1 Vertragsgegenstand"><Clause><Text>Lieferung von Komponenten gemäß Anhang A nach Einzelbestellungen des Käufers. Lieferung von Komponenten gemäß Anhang A nach Einzelbestellungen des Käufers. Lieferung von Komponenten Typ K-100 gemäß Spezifikation (Anhang 1) und Zeichnungen (Anhang 2).</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Delivery of components according to Annex A at the buyer's individual orders.

Delivery of components according to Annex A at the buyer's individual orders.

Delivery of components Type K-100 according to specification (Annex 1) and drawings (Annex 2).</Description><Justification>This variant is most favorable to the customer as it ensures that all components, including the specific Type K-100, are delivered exactly according to the agreed specifications and drawings. This provides the highest level of assurance that the customer's requirements are met.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We need to ensure that all components, especially the critical Type K-100, are delivered precisely as specified to maintain the quality and functionality of our final product.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Delivery of components according to Annex A at the buyer's individual orders.

Delivery of components according to Annex A at the buyer's individual orders.

Delivery of components Type K-100 according to specification (Annex 1).</Description><Justification>This variant is balanced as it still ensures the delivery of components according to the agreed specifications, but it does not include the drawings for Type K-100. This could be acceptable if the specification alone is sufficient for the customer's needs.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>While we understand the importance of the specification, we believe that including the drawings for Type K-100 would provide additional clarity and ensure accurate delivery.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Delivery of components according to Annex A at the buyer's individual orders.

Delivery of components according to Annex A at the buyer's individual orders.

Delivery of components Type K-100.</Description><Justification>This variant is acceptable as it still ensures the delivery of components, including Type K-100, but it does not include the specification or drawings. This could be acceptable if the customer has alternative means of ensuring the components meet their requirements.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Although we can accept the delivery of Type K-100 components without the specification and drawings, we would prefer to have these included to ensure the components meet our exact needs.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Delivery of components at the buyer's individual orders.

Delivery of components at the buyer's individual orders.

Delivery of components.</Description><Justification>This variant is unacceptable to the customer as it does not provide any assurance that the components will be delivered according to the agreed specifications or that they will include the critical Type K-100 components. This leaves too much room for error and could jeopardize the customer's final product.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We cannot accept this variant as it does not guarantee that the components will be delivered according to our specifications or that they will include the Type K-100 components. This is a critical requirement for us and we need this assurance in the agreement.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 2 Qualität und Gewährleistung"><Clause><Text>(1) Der Lieferant sichert zu, dass die Ware den Spezifikationen in Anhang A entspricht und handelsübliche Qualität aufweist. (2) Die Gewährleistungsfrist beträgt 24 Monate ab Lieferung. (3) Bei Mängeln hat der Käufer das Recht auf Nacherfüllung (Wahlrecht beim Käufer). Kosten der Nacherfüllung trägt der Lieferant, mit Ausnahme von Aus- und Einbaukosten, die nur bei Verschulden des Lieferanten ersetzt werden. (4) Mängel sind unverzüglich, spätestens innerhalb von 7 Werktagen nach Erhalt (offene Mängel) bzw. Entdeckung (versteckte Mängel) schriftlich zu rügen. (1) Der Lieferant sichert zu, dass die Ware den Spezifikationen in Anhang A entspricht und handelsübliche Qualität aufweist. (2) Die Gewährleistungsfrist beträgt 24 Monate ab Lieferung. (3) Bei Mängeln hat der Käufer das Recht auf Nacherfüllung (Wahlrecht beim Käufer). Kosten der Nacherfüllung trägt der Lieferant, mit Ausnahme von Aus- und Einbaukosten, die nur bei Verschulden des Lieferanten ersetzt werden. (4) Mängel sind unverzüglich, spätestens innerhalb von 7 Werktagen nach Erhalt (offene Mängel) bzw. Entdeckung (versteckte Mängel) schriftlich zu rügen. Der Lieferant sichert zu, dass die Ware den Spezifikationen entspricht und frei von Sach- und Rechtsmängeln ist. Qualitätssicherung nach ISO 9001 wird angestrebt. Gewährleistungsfrist: 24 Monate ab Lieferung. Bei Mängeln erfolgt Nacherfüllung nach Wahl des Lieferanten (Nachbesserung oder Ersatzlieferung). Schlägt die Nacherfüllung fehl, hat der Kunde das Recht auf Minderung oder Rücktritt. Aus- und Einbaukosten werden nur bei Verschulden des Lieferanten und nach vorheriger Abstimmung übernommen. Rügefrist nach § 377 HGB: Offene Mängel unverzüglich (innerhalb von 5 Werktagen), versteckte Mängel unverzüglich nach Entdeckung (innerhalb von 5 Werktagen).</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Extended warranty period with full coverage of rectification costs.</Description><Justification>This variant offers the longest warranty period and full coverage of rectification costs, providing the highest level of protection for the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Given the critical nature of the goods for our operations, we need the extended warranty period and full cost coverage to ensure minimal disruption and financial risk.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Standard warranty period with shared rectification costs.</Description><Justification>This variant balances the interests of both parties, providing a reasonable warranty period and shared responsibility for rectification costs.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This approach acknowledges both our need for quality assurance and your need to manage costs, striking a fair balance.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Reduced warranty period with limited rectification cost coverage.</Description><Justification>While not ideal, this variant still provides some level of protection and could be acceptable if other terms are favorable.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Although we prefer a longer warranty period, we could accept this if other aspects of the deal, such as price or delivery terms, are adjusted in our favor.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Minimal warranty period with no rectification cost coverage.</Description><Justification>This variant offers minimal protection and places all the risk on the customer, making it unacceptable.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This level of warranty and cost coverage is insufficient for our needs and would expose us to unacceptable risks. We cannot agree to these terms.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 3 Lieferung und Verzug"><Clause><Text>(1) Angegebene Liefertermine sind Richtwerte, aber nach Bestätigung durch den Lieferanten verbindlich. Lieferung erfolgt DAP Werk Musterstadt (Incoterms 2020).40 (2) Bei schuldhaftem Verzug haftet der Lieferant für den nachgewiesenen Verzögerungsschaden bis maximal 5% des jeweiligen Bestellwerts. (1) Angegebene Liefertermine sind Richtwerte, aber nach Bestömung durch den Lieferanten verbindlich. Lieferung erfolgt DAP Werk Musterstadt (Incoterms 2020). Liefertermine sind ca.-Termine, werden aber nach Bestätigung angestrebt. Lieferung FCA Hamburg (Incoterms 2020). Bei schuldhaftem Verzug um mehr als 10 Werktage kann der Kunde nach Setzung einer angemessenen Nachfrist vom Vertrag zurücktreten. Schadensersatz für Verzug ist auf 50% des vorhersehbaren Schadens begrenzt.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Delivery dates are approximate but become binding after confirmation by the supplier. Delivery takes place DAP Werk Musterstadt (Incoterms 2020). In case of culpable delay, the supplier is liable for the proven delay damage up to a maximum of 5% of the respective order value.</Description><Justification>This variant is most favorable to the customer as it provides clear and binding delivery terms with a specified liability for delay damages.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This clause ensures that the supplier is committed to the delivery dates and takes responsibility for any delays, providing the customer with a reliable delivery schedule and compensation for delays.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Delivery dates are approximate but become binding after confirmation by the supplier. Delivery takes place DAP Werk Musterstadt (Incoterms 2020). In case of culpable delay of more than 10 working days, the customer can withdraw from the contract after setting a reasonable grace period. Compensation for delay is limited to 50% of the foreseeable damage.</Description><Justification>This variant offers a balanced approach by providing binding delivery dates and a reasonable compensation for delays, while also giving the supplier some flexibility.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This clause balances the interests of both parties by ensuring commitment to delivery dates and providing compensation for delays, while also allowing the supplier some leeway in case of unforeseen circumstances.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Delivery dates are approximate but will be pursued after confirmation. Delivery FCA Hamburg (Incoterms 2020). In case of culpable delay of more than 10 working days, the customer can withdraw from the contract after setting a reasonable grace period. Compensation for delay is limited to 50% of the foreseeable damage.</Description><Justification>This variant is acceptable to the customer as it provides some assurance on delivery dates and compensation for delays, but it is less favorable due to the change in delivery terms.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>While this clause provides some assurance on delivery dates and compensation for delays, the change in delivery terms to FCA Hamburg shifts more responsibility to the customer, making it less favorable.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Delivery dates are approximate and non-binding. Delivery FCA Hamburg (Incoterms 2020). The supplier is not liable for any delay damages.</Description><Justification>This variant is unacceptable to the customer as it provides no assurance on delivery dates and no compensation for delays, while also shifting more responsibility to the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This clause is not in the customer's best interest as it provides no commitment to delivery dates, no compensation for delays, and shifts more responsibility to the customer, making it unacceptable.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 4 Preise und Zahlungsbedingungen"><Clause><Text>(1) Preise gemäß aktueller Preisliste des Lieferanten (Anhang B), Anpassungen vorbehalten mit 4 Wochen Vorankündigung. (2) Zahlung: 30 Tage nach Rechnungseingang mit 2% Skonto, oder 45 Tage netto.127 (1) Preise gemäß aktueller Preisliste des Lieferanten (Anhang B), Anpassungen vorbehalten mit 4 Wochen Vorankündigung. (2) Zahlung: 30 Tage nach Rechnungseingang mit 2% Skonto, oder 45 Tage netto.</Text><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Prices are subject to the supplier's current price list (Annex B), with adjustments reserved with 4 weeks' notice.</Description><Justification>This clause allows the supplier to unilaterally change prices with only a short notice period, which can lead to financial uncertainty and budgeting difficulties for the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We propose fixing prices for a minimum of 12 months to ensure budget stability and predictability. Alternatively, any price adjustments should be mutually agreed upon with a longer notice period, such as 3 months.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Prices are subject to the supplier's current price list (Annex B), with adjustments reserved with 8 weeks' notice.</Description><Justification>While this clause still allows the supplier to change prices, the extended notice period gives the customer more time to adjust budgets and seek alternative suppliers if necessary.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We suggest extending the notice period to 12 weeks to provide even more flexibility for our budgeting and procurement processes. Additionally, we propose that any price increases be capped at a certain percentage annually.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Prices are subject to the supplier's current price list (Annex B), with adjustments reserved with 12 weeks' notice and a maximum increase of 5% annually.</Description><Justification>This clause balances the supplier's need to adjust prices with the customer's need for predictability. The 12-week notice period and the cap on annual increases provide stability for the customer's budgeting process.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We agree to this clause as it provides a reasonable balance between our needs and the supplier's requirements. However, we propose that the annual cap be reduced to 3% to better align with our budgeting constraints.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Prices are fixed for 24 months, with any adjustments thereafter subject to mutual agreement and a 6-month notice period.</Description><Justification>This clause provides the highest level of price stability and predictability for the customer, allowing for effective long-term budgeting and planning.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We strongly advocate for this clause as it ensures long-term price stability, which is crucial for our financial planning. The 6-month notice period for any adjustments after the initial 24 months provides ample time for us to review and negotiate any changes.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 5 Haftung"><Clause><Text>(1) Die Haftung des Lieferanten für leichte Fahrlässigkeit ist ausgeschlossen, es sei denn, es handelt sich um die Verletzung von Kardinalpflichten oder Schäden an Leben, Körper, Gesundheit. Bei leicht fahrlässiger Verletzung von Kardinalpflichten ist die Haftung auf den vertragstypischen, vorhersehbaren Schaden begrenzt.4 (2) Die Haftung für mittelbare Schäden und entgangenen Gewinn ist bei leichter Fahrlässigkeit ausgeschlossen. (1) Die Haftung des Lieferanten für leichte Fahrlässigkeit ist ausgeschlossen, es sei denn, es handelt sich um die Verletzung von Kardinalpflichten oder Schäden an Leben, Körper, Gesundheit. Bei leicht fahrlässiger Verletzung von Kardinalpflichten ist die Haftung auf den vertragstypischen, vorhersehbaren Schaden begrenzt. (2) Die Haftung für mittelbare Schäden und entgangenen Gewinn ist bei leichter Fahrlässigkeit ausgeschlossen. Die Haftung des Auftragnehmers ist auf Vorsatz und grobe Fahrlässigkeit beschränkt. Dies gilt nicht für Schäden an Leben, Körper, Gesundheit und bei Verletzung von Kardinalpflichten. Bei leicht fahrlässiger Verletzung von Kardinalpflichten ist die Haftung auf den Auftragswert begrenzt.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Remove all liability limitations for the supplier.</Description><Justification>This variant completely removes any liability limitations for the supplier, ensuring that the customer is fully protected against any damages, whether direct or indirect, and regardless of the degree of negligence.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This position maximizes the customer's protection but may be strongly resisted by the supplier due to the increased risk and liability exposure.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Maintain liability for gross negligence and intent, but include partial liability for slight negligence, capped at a reasonable amount.</Description><Justification>This variant balances the interests of both parties by maintaining full liability for serious misconduct while limiting liability for minor negligence to a reasonable cap.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This approach provides a fair compromise, offering the customer substantial protection while not overly burdening the supplier with unlimited liability for minor issues.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Accept liability limitations for slight negligence but insist on full liability for gross negligence and intentional acts.</Description><Justification>This variant accepts some risk by limiting liability for minor negligence but ensures that the supplier is fully accountable for more serious misconduct.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>While this position involves some compromise, it ensures that the customer is protected against major risks and can be presented as a reasonable middle ground.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Accept full liability exclusion for the supplier, including for gross negligence and intentional acts.</Description><Justification>This variant places the customer at significant risk by accepting full liability exclusion, providing no protection against supplier misconduct, whether minor or serious.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This position is highly unfavorable to the customer and should only be considered if there are no other viable options or if the supplier has overwhelming negotiating power.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 6 Geheimhaltung"><Clause><Text>Die Parteien vereinbaren Stillschweigen über die Konditionen dieses Vertrages. Die Parteien vereinbaren Stillschweigen über die Konditionen dieses Vertrages. Gegenseitige Geheimhaltungspflicht bezüglich vertraulicher Informationen. Beide Parteien bekennen sich zur Einhaltung der Grundsätze des LkSG und informieren sich gegenseitig bei relevanten Risiken.</Text><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Both parties agree to maintain confidentiality regarding the terms of this agreement. Mutual confidentiality regarding confidential information. Both parties commit to adhering to the principles of the LkSG and inform each other about relevant risks.</Description><Justification>This variant ensures mutual confidentiality and compliance with LkSG principles, protecting both parties' interests while allowing for necessary risk information sharing.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This approach balances the need for confidentiality with the importance of risk management and compliance with legal obligations.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Both parties agree to maintain confidentiality regarding the terms of this agreement. No mutual confidentiality regarding confidential information. Only one party commits to adhering to the principles of the LkSG and informs the other about relevant risks.</Description><Justification>This variant lacks mutual confidentiality and commitment to LkSG principles from both parties, creating an imbalance and potential risks for the non-committed party.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This approach is one-sided and does not provide equal protection or compliance assurance for both parties, which is unfair and could lead to disputes.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Both parties agree to maintain confidentiality regarding the terms of this agreement. Mutual confidentiality regarding confidential information. Both parties commit to adhering to the principles of the LkSG and inform each other about relevant risks, with a clear process for risk mitigation.</Description><Justification>This variant ensures mutual confidentiality and compliance with LkSG principles, while also providing a structured approach to risk management, benefiting both parties.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This approach not only balances confidentiality and compliance but also enhances risk management through a clear process, ensuring both parties are protected and informed.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Both parties agree to maintain confidentiality regarding the terms of this agreement. Mutual confidentiality regarding confidential information. Both parties commit to adhering to the principles of the LkSG and inform each other about relevant risks, with regular audits and a dispute resolution mechanism.</Description><Justification>This variant ensures the highest level of mutual confidentiality and compliance with LkSG principles, along with regular audits and a dispute resolution mechanism, providing the most robust protection for both parties.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This approach offers the most comprehensive protection, ensuring confidentiality, compliance, regular audits, and a clear dispute resolution mechanism, which is highly beneficial for both parties.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 7 LkSG-Konformität"><Clause><Text>Der Lieferant bestätigt, die Grundsätze des LkSG zu beachten und auf Anfrage Auskunft zu erteilen.100 Der Lieferant bestätigt, die Grundsätze des LkSG zu beachten und auf Anfrage Auskunft zu erteilen.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>The supplier confirms to comply with the principles of the LkSG and to provide information upon request, with an additional clause specifying regular audits and penalties for non-compliance.</Description><Justification>This variant is most favorable as it ensures the highest level of compliance and accountability from the supplier, with regular checks and consequences for non-adherence.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Regular audits and penalties will ensure that the supplier remains committed to the principles of the LkSG, providing us with the assurance that our supply chain is ethical and compliant.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>The supplier confirms to comply with the principles of the LkSG and to provide information upon request, with an additional clause specifying regular self-assessments by the supplier.</Description><Justification>This variant balances the need for compliance with the practicalities of implementation, allowing the supplier to self-regulate while still providing assurance.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Regular self-assessments will enable the supplier to monitor their compliance effectively, while also providing us with the necessary reports to ensure adherence to the LkSG principles.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>The supplier confirms to comply with the principles of the LkSG and to provide information upon request, with no additional clauses.</Description><Justification>This variant is acceptable as it meets the basic requirements of the LkSG, ensuring that the supplier is aware of and committed to the principles.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>While this variant meets the basic requirements, adding regular self-assessments or audits would provide additional assurance of compliance and strengthen our partnership.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>The supplier confirms to comply with the principles of the LkSG but does not agree to provide information upon request.</Description><Justification>This variant is unacceptable as it does not meet the basic requirements of the LkSG, leaving us without the means to verify the supplier's compliance.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>The ability to request information is crucial for ensuring compliance with the LkSG. Without this clause, we cannot verify the supplier's adherence to the principles, which is a non-negotiable requirement.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 8 Schlussbestimmungen"><Clause><Text>(1) Deutsches Recht unter Ausschluss UN-Kaufrecht. Gerichtsstand: Musterstadt. (2) Schriftformklausel. Salvatorische Klausel.2 (1) Deutsches Recht unter Ausschluss UN-Kaufrecht. Gerichtsstand: Musterstadt. (2) Schriftformklausel. Salvatorische Klausel. Deutsches Recht (ohne UN-Kaufrecht). Gerichtsstand Köln. Schriftform. Salvatorische Klausel. Deutsches Recht (ohne UN-Kaufrecht). Gerichtsstand Duisburg. Sollten Teile unwirksam sein, gilt der Rest.</Text><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>The clause specifies German law excluding the UN Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods (CISG) and sets the jurisdiction in 'Musterstadt'.</Description><Justification>This clause is unacceptable because it limits the customer's legal recourse to German law and a specific jurisdiction, which may not be favorable or convenient for the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We propose removing the specification of German law and the exclusive jurisdiction to allow for more flexibility and fairness in dispute resolution.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>The clause includes a written form requirement and a severability clause, which are standard contractual provisions.</Description><Justification>These clauses are acceptable as they provide clarity and ensure that the contract remains valid even if parts are found to be invalid.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We agree to include the written form requirement and severability clause as they are standard and beneficial for both parties.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>The clause specifies German law excluding the UN Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods (CISG) and sets the jurisdiction in Cologne, with a written form requirement and a severability clause.</Description><Justification>This clause is balanced as it provides a clear legal framework and jurisdiction while including standard contractual protections.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We can accept this clause as it provides a clear legal framework and jurisdiction while including standard contractual protections.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>The clause specifies German law excluding the UN Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods (CISG) and sets the jurisdiction in Duisburg, with a provision stating that if parts are invalid, the rest remains valid.</Description><Justification>This clause is most favorable as it provides a clear legal framework and jurisdiction, with a provision ensuring the contract's validity even if parts are found invalid.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We strongly support this clause as it provides a clear legal framework and jurisdiction, with a provision ensuring the contract's validity even if parts are found invalid.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="Preise &amp; Zahlung"><Clause><Text>Preise gemäß Angebot vom [Datum]. Preisanpassungen sind jährlich möglich bei nachgewiesenen Kostensteigerungen &gt; 5% (z.B. Materialpreisgleitklausel bezogen auf Index XYZ). Zahlung: 30 Tage netto nach Rechnungseingang. Preise gemäß jeweils aktueller Preisliste des Verkäufers. Zahlung: 30 Tage netto ab Rechnungsdatum.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Prices fixed for the duration of the contract with no annual adjustments.</Description><Justification>This variant eliminates the risk of price increases for the customer, providing certainty and stability in costs.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>In uncertain economic times, our company requires stability in pricing to manage our budget effectively. We propose that prices remain fixed for the duration of the contract to achieve this stability.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Prices adjusted annually based on a mutually agreed-upon index, with a cap on increases.</Description><Justification>This variant allows for some adjustment due to cost increases but protects the customer from excessive hikes.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>While we understand that costs may increase, we propose a balanced approach where prices are adjusted annually based on a mutually agreed-upon index, with a cap on increases to protect our budget from significant fluctuations.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Prices adjusted annually with a clear formula for calculation and a right to terminate if increases exceed a certain threshold.</Description><Justification>This variant provides transparency in price adjustments and gives the customer an option to exit if increases are too high.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We can accept annual price adjustments provided there is a clear formula for calculation and we have the right to terminate the contract if the increases exceed a certain threshold. This ensures transparency and protects our interests.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Prices subject to annual adjustments at the seller's discretion without clear criteria or caps.</Description><Justification>This variant leaves the customer vulnerable to unpredictable and potentially significant price increases, offering no protection or stability.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We cannot accept a clause that allows for annual price adjustments at the seller's discretion without clear criteria or caps. This would expose our company to unpredictable costs and make budget planning impossible. We need more stability and predictability in pricing.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="Haftung"><Clause><Text>Haftung für Vorsatz und grobe Fahrlässigkeit ist unbeschränkt. Haftung für leichte Fahrlässigkeit ist ausgeschlossen, außer bei Verletzung von Kardinalpflichten und Schäden an Leben, Körper, Gesundheit. Bei leicht fahrlässiger Verletzung von Kardinalpflichten ist die Haftung auf den Auftragswert begrenzt. Haftung ist auf Vorsatz und grobe Fahrlässigkeit beschränkt, außer bei Schäden an Leben, Körper, Gesundheit. Haftung für leichte Fahrlässigkeit, auch bei Kardinalpflichtverletzung, ist ausgeschlossen.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Unlimited liability for gross negligence and intent, with limited liability for slight negligence in cardinal duties. Liability for slight negligence in non-cardinal duties is excluded.</Description><Justification>This variant provides the most protection for the customer by ensuring that the provider is held accountable for all types of negligence, with limited exceptions.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This approach aligns with industry standards and ensures that our interests are fully protected.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Unlimited liability for gross negligence and intent. Limited liability for slight negligence in cardinal duties, capped at the contract value. Liability for slight negligence in non-cardinal duties is excluded.</Description><Justification>This variant offers a balanced approach, providing reasonable protection for the customer while acknowledging the provider's limitations.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This balanced approach ensures fairness for both parties and is a common practice in similar agreements.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Liability limited to gross negligence and intent, except for damages to life, body, or health. Liability for slight negligence in cardinal duties is capped at the contract value.</Description><Justification>While this variant provides less protection, it still ensures that the provider is held accountable for the most serious types of negligence.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Although this approach offers less protection, it is still within acceptable risk parameters for our organization.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Liability limited to gross negligence and intent, with no liability for slight negligence, even in cardinal duties.</Description><Justification>This variant provides minimal protection for the customer and places most of the risk on the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This approach is unacceptable as it places an unfair burden of risk on our organization and does not align with our risk management policies.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="Gegenstand"><Clause><Text>Lieferung von Elektronikkomponenten (Liste in Anhang 1) gemäß den technischen Spezifikationen (Anhang 2). Lieferung von Standard-Kunststoffteilen gemäß Katalog Verkäufer (Stand [Datum]).</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>The customer wants the supplier to ensure that the electronic components meet the latest industry standards and certifications, with the supplier bearing all costs for any updates or changes in these standards.</Description><Justification>This variant is most favorable to the customer as it ensures the highest quality and compliance with industry standards, while shifting all associated costs and risks to the supplier.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>To guarantee the best performance and regulatory compliance of the final product, it is crucial that the electronic components adhere to the most recent industry standards and certifications. As the supplier is the expert in this field, they should be responsible for any updates or changes, including all associated costs.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>The customer agrees to accept the electronic components as long as they meet the technical specifications provided in Anhang 2, with a clause allowing for joint review and updates if industry standards change significantly.</Description><Justification>This variant balances the interests of both parties by ensuring the components meet the agreed specifications, while also providing a mechanism for addressing significant changes in industry standards.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>While the customer is willing to accept the components based on the agreed specifications, it is important to include a provision for joint review and updates in case of significant changes in industry standards. This approach ensures that both parties share the responsibility for maintaining the quality and compliance of the components.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>The customer will accept the electronic components based on the supplier's current standards, with the customer bearing the cost of any updates or changes required to meet the latest industry standards.</Description><Justification>Although this variant places more responsibility and cost on the customer, it is still acceptable as it allows the customer to ensure the components meet their specific needs and industry standards.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>The customer is willing to accept the components based on the supplier's current standards but reserves the right to make updates or changes to meet the latest industry standards. While the customer will bear the cost of these updates, this approach ensures that the final product meets the customer's quality and compliance requirements.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>The supplier will provide electronic components based on their own standards, with no guarantee that they will meet the customer's technical specifications or any industry standards.</Description><Justification>This variant is unacceptable to the customer as it provides no assurance that the components will meet the required technical specifications or industry standards, potentially compromising the quality and compliance of the final product.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>The customer cannot accept a situation where the supplier provides components based solely on their own standards, with no guarantee of meeting the agreed technical specifications or industry standards. This approach poses significant risks to the quality and compliance of the final product, which is not acceptable to the customer.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 1 Leistungsumfang"><Clause><Text>Herstellung und Lieferung von Gussteilen gemäß Spezifikation AG-Guss-001 (Anlage).</Text><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Reject the clause entirely.</Description><Justification>The clause is too vague and does not provide sufficient details about the quality standards, delivery timelines, or liability for defects.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We need more specific terms to ensure our quality requirements are met and to manage our production schedules effectively.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Request addition of quality inspection criteria.</Description><Justification>While the clause specifies the production according to AG-Guss-001, it lacks details on how quality will be ensured.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>To ensure the parts meet our standards, we need to include specific quality inspection criteria and the frequency of inspections.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Propose inclusion of delivery timelines and penalties for delays.</Description><Justification>The clause does not address the critical aspect of delivery timelines, which is essential for our production planning.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We need to set clear delivery timelines and penalties for delays to ensure our production schedules are not disrupted.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Insist on a comprehensive warranty and liability clause for defective parts.</Description><Justification>The current clause does not protect our interests in case of defects or failures in the cast parts.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>To safeguard our interests, we need a comprehensive warranty and liability clause that covers defects and ensures quick replacement or compensation.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 2 Qualität"><Clause><Text>Der Auftragnehmer sicht die Einhaltung der Spezifikation und übliche Gussqualität zu. Gewährleistungsfrist: 18 Monate ab Lieferung. Nacherfüllung nach Wahl des Auftragnehmers. Kosten trägt der Auftragnehmer, jedoch ohne Aus- und Einbaukosten. Rügefrist § 377 HGB: 5 Werktage für offene, 7 Werktage nach Entdeckung für versteckte Mängel. Qualität gemäß Datenblatt. Geringfügige Abweichungen sind zulässig. Gewährleistung: 24 Monate ab Lieferung. Nacherfüllung nach Wahl des Verkäufers. Käufer trägt Kosten für Aus- und Einbau. Rügefrist § 377 HGB: 3 Werktage für offene, 5 Werktage nach Entdeckung für versteckte Mängel.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Extend the warranty period to 36 months and ensure the supplier covers all costs, including installation and removal costs.</Description><Justification>This variant provides the longest warranty period and the most comprehensive cost coverage, ensuring minimal financial risk for the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>A longer warranty period and comprehensive cost coverage will provide us with greater security and demonstrate your commitment to the quality of your products.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Maintain the warranty period at 24 months, but negotiate for the supplier to cover installation and removal costs.</Description><Justification>This variant balances the warranty period with additional cost coverage, providing a reasonable compromise between risk and benefit.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>Covering installation and removal costs will show your willingness to stand behind your products and provide us with added value without extending the warranty period.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Accept the 24-month warranty period with the customer covering installation and removal costs, but negotiate for a more flexible notice period for defects.</Description><Justification>This variant accepts the current warranty terms but seeks to improve the notice period for defects, providing some additional protection for the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>A more flexible notice period for defects will allow us to better manage our quality control processes and demonstrate your understanding of our operational needs.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Reduce the warranty period to 18 months and require the customer to cover all costs, including installation and removal costs.</Description><Justification>This variant significantly reduces the warranty period and shifts all costs to the customer, representing a high level of risk and burden.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>A shorter warranty period and shifting all costs to us is not acceptable as it increases our risk and financial burden significantly. We need a more balanced agreement that reflects our long-term partnership goals.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 3 Lieferung"><Clause><Text>Liefertermine sind Planungstermine. Lieferung FCA Duisburg (Incoterms 2020). Verzugsschaden nur bei grober Fahrlässigkeit oder Vorsatz des Auftragnehmers. Lieferzeiten sind unverbindliche Schätzungen. Lieferung EXW Leipzig (Incoterms 2020). Keine Haftung für Lieferverzug, außer bei Vorsatz oder grober Fahrlässigkeit.</Text><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Delivery dates are planning dates. Delivery FCA Duisburg (Incoterms 2020).</Description><Justification>This clause is unacceptable because it imposes a strict delivery schedule on the customer without any flexibility. The delivery term FCA Duisburg also places the responsibility for the goods on the customer once they are loaded on the delivery vehicle, which is not favorable for the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We propose changing the delivery term to DDP (Delivered Duty Paid) to our designated location. This would ensure that the supplier takes full responsibility for the delivery, including customs clearance and all risks until the goods are delivered to our doorstep.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Delay damage only in case of gross negligence or intent of the contractor.</Description><Justification>This clause is acceptable as it provides some protection to the customer in case of significant delays caused by the contractor's gross negligence or intentional actions.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We can accept this clause as it provides a reasonable level of protection for our interests. However, we would like to ensure that the definition of 'gross negligence' is clearly outlined in the contract to avoid any misunderstandings.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Delivery times are non-binding estimates. Delivery EXW Leipzig (Incoterms 2020).</Description><Justification>This clause is most favorable to the customer as it provides flexibility in delivery times and the delivery term EXW Leipzig places the minimum responsibility on the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We are satisfied with this clause as it allows us the flexibility to plan our operations without being strictly bound by delivery times. The EXW Leipzig term also ensures that we have control over the transport and insurance of the goods from the supplier's warehouse.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>No liability for delivery delay, except in case of intent or gross negligence.</Description><Justification>This clause is balanced as it provides some protection to the customer in case of significant delays caused by the supplier's intentional actions or gross negligence, while also acknowledging that minor delays can occur.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We can accept this clause with a slight modification. We propose adding a notification requirement where the supplier must inform us of any potential delays as soon as they become aware of them. This will allow us to adjust our plans accordingly and mitigate any potential impacts.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="§ 4 Preis und Zahlung"><Clause><Text>Preise gemäß Angebot, Anpassung bei Rohstoffpreisänderung &gt; 10% vorbehalten. Zahlung: 30 Tage netto.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>Fixed prices for the entire contract duration with no adjustments.</Description><Justification>This variant provides the highest level of price predictability and budget stability for the customer.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>In today's volatile market, our organization needs stability. We are looking for long term partners who can provide fixed pricing. We are happy to negotiate other terms, but we need to fix pricing.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>Prices as quoted, with adjustments only if raw material prices change by more than 20%.</Description><Justification>This variant offers a balance between price stability and flexibility for the supplier.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We understand raw material prices can fluctuate. However, we need to have a balance between market conditions and our budget. We are willing to accept a 20% threshold to ensure both parties are protected.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>Prices as quoted, with adjustments if raw material prices change by more than 15%.</Description><Justification>This variant is acceptable but provides less price stability for the customer compared to the most favorable or balanced variants.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We are willing to meet you in the middle and accept a 15% threshold. However, we need to be clear on when this clause can be invoked and prices can change.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>Prices as quoted, with adjustments if raw material prices change by more than 10%.</Description><Justification>This variant provides too much uncertainty for the customer's budget planning.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>This clause is too volatile for our budget planning. We need more stability in pricing. We are happy to discuss other terms, but this clause is not acceptable in its current form.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section><Section title="Sonstiges"><Clause><Text>Deutsches Recht (ohne UN-Kaufrecht). Gerichtsstand Leipzig. Salvatorische Klausel.</Text><Variant classification="Most Favorable"><Description>German law (excluding UN Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods).</Description><Justification>The clause specifies German law but excludes the UN Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods (CISG), which could provide additional protections for international sales. This is most favorable as it avoids potential complexities and uncertainties associated with the CISG.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We prefer to keep the clause as is, specifying German law without the CISG, to ensure clarity and predictability in our contractual relationship.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Balanced"><Description>German law (including UN Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods). Jurisdiction: Leipzig. Severability clause.</Description><Justification>This variant includes the CISG, which can be beneficial for international sales contracts, but retains German law and the jurisdiction of Leipzig. The severability clause ensures that the rest of the contract remains valid if any part is found invalid.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We propose including the CISG to benefit from its international sales provisions, while keeping German law and Leipzig as the jurisdiction. The severability clause adds an extra layer of contractual security.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Acceptable"><Description>German law (including UN Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods). Jurisdiction: Leipzig or the courts of the customer's place of business. Severability clause.</Description><Justification>This variant is acceptable as it includes the CISG and provides flexibility in jurisdiction, allowing for Leipzig or the customer's place of business. This can be more convenient for the customer while still maintaining the severability clause.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We suggest including the CISG and allowing for jurisdiction in either Leipzig or our place of business. This provides us with more flexibility and convenience in case of disputes, while the severability clause ensures contractual stability.</NegotiationArgument></Variant><Variant classification="Unacceptable"><Description>German law (excluding UN Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods). Jurisdiction: Seller's place of business. No severability clause.</Description><Justification>This variant is unacceptable as it excludes the CISG, specifies the seller's place of business for jurisdiction, which could be inconvenient, and lacks a severability clause, potentially invalidating the entire contract if any part is found invalid.</Justification><NegotiationArgument>We cannot accept a clause that excludes the CISG, specifies the seller's place of business for jurisdiction, and lacks a severability clause. This puts us at a significant disadvantage in terms of legal protections and convenience.</NegotiationArgument></Variant></Clause></Section></Playbook>
